TONIMARIE MORRIS

High-performing Sales Consultant and Account Manager turned Software Engineer creating clean and responsive applications optimized for outstanding user experiences. I leverage my analytical skills, strong work ethic, and full-stack development experience to excel in fast-paced, metrics-driven environments.

SKILLS

JavaScript / HTML5 / CSS3 / SCSS / React / jQuery / Node / Express / MongoDB / PostgreSQL / Ruby on Rails

EXPERIENCE

Patrick Fritz for Delegate, Remote – Front End Software Engineer 2021

- Reverse engineered legacy website to implement critical updates.
- Maintained, monitored, and updated campaign website.
- Documented page views/increases.

4th Street Manor, Remote – Designer & Software Engineer 2021

- Designed/developed a responsive website from scratch with no template.
- Chose lightweight tech stack (HTML/CSS/JavaScript) ease of portability and maintainability.
- Ensured final site was accessible for screen readers while maintaining a modern aesthetic.

Bit by Bit Coding, Remote – Instructor 2021

- Provided comprehensive JavaScript fundamental instruction, including loops, conditionals, methods and functions to 8 Middle School students.
- Coordinated one-on-one and group instruction to meet students' individual learning needs.
- Led instruction on developer console and debugging.

<u>Additional Experience:</u> Account Manager – Star Valley Provisions (2017 - 2020) | Sales Associate/Repair Technician – Batteries Plus Bulbs (2016 - 2018) | Cellular Sales Representative (2006 - 2015) - nTelos Wireless, Verizon Wireless, US Cellular

EDUCATION

General Assembly, Remote – Software Engineering Immersive Program 2020

Intensive 12-week, 450+ hour full stack engineering program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

Lyrics Mobile: Utilized React Native to develop a mobile lyric search/list creation application.

Impulse: Developed a full-stack e-commerce app using MongoDB, Express, React, and Node.

Portfolio: Designed a mobile-first, responsive website with HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, and a Google Sheets API.

My Dictionary: Created a responsive dictionary app using React, SCSS, and Merriam-Webster's dictionary API.

Tunr: Built a full-stack playlist creation app with Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, and React.

<u>Additional Education:</u> Bluefield State College – Business Administration Classes

HONORS

- Top Salesperson in East Region (2012) Verizon Wireless
- Highest Accessory Sales (2015) nTelos Wireless